Manuel Sexto Freire

16/06/1998

+34 664 74 83 73

manusexto98@gmail.com Linkedin

Professional profile

Professional with a background in Economics and a current Master's in Business Intelligence, experienced in data analysis, client management, and problem-solving in financial and business environments. Skilled in handling large datasets, applying quantitative and qualitative analysis techniques, and presenting clear results for strategic decision-making.

Professional experience

09/2024 - Present

Science and Marketing - Internship

Madrid, Spain

- Market analysis to identify opportunities and collaboration in creating strategies to optimize resources and increase competitiveness.
- Application of pattern and trend analysis in digital marketing and social media to improve customer conversion and engagement.

10/2023 - 10/2024

Abanca - Client Specialist Manager

A Coruña, Spain

- Managed and analyzed client portfolio data using the company's CRM to identify behavioral patterns and business opportunities.
- Created reports and conducted client analyses extracted from the CRM, enhancing understanding of client profiles and supporting strategic decisionmaking.
- Coordinated with other departments to ensure effective data integration and resolve issues related to customer experience

04/2023 - 07/2023

Grupo Externa - Internship

A Coruña, Spain

- Utilized data analysis to improve the efficiency of the recruitment process.
- Maintained and managed candidate databases using data cleaning and segmentation techniques.

06/2019 - 09/2021

Carrefour - Supermarket cashier

A Coruña, Spain

Education

Universidad Internacional de La Rioja, UNIR

A Coruña, Spain

Master's in Business Intelligence (Ongoinng)

2023

Universidade da Coruña, UDC

A Coruña, Spain

Bachelor's Degreee in Economics

Erasmus Exchange Program

09/21 – 07/22

Comenius University

Bratislava, Slovaquia

09/16 - 06/18

Universidade de Santiago de Compostela, UDC Bachelor's Degree in History (Not Finished)

Santiago de Compostela, Spain

Technical skills

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

Microsoft SQL

Microsoft Power BI

Tableau

Python y R

Certifications & Training

Power BI - IBM SkillsBuild & datahack

Languages

Spanish: Native

English: C1

Galician: Native